FBI Confidential Files on Communist Activity in the Entertainment Industry and FBI Surveillance Files on Hollywood on Microfilm 6111 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- News clippings - October 1947 cont.-March 1949. (Reel 9)
  - Volume 14., 1948; 6 (Reel 9)
    January 1948-February 1948. 88 pp.: "Hollywood 10" hearings; "Hollywood 10" law suits against studios; Screen Actors Guild's non-Communist oath policy; Tenney Committee [California Senate Un-American Activities Committees] hearings; Eric Johnston; Edward Dmytryck; House Labor Subcommittee investigations of IATSE-CSU jurisdictional strike; Hungarian ban on US films.
  - Volume 15., 1948; 7 (Reel 9)
    March 1948-May 1948. 143 pp.: "Hollywood 10" law suits against studios; legal defense of "Hollywood 10"; blacklisting issue; international film community's response to Hollywood "inquisition"; anti-Communist films; John Howard Lawson; "Hollywood 10" contempt trials; Dalton Trumbo; protests against The Iron Curtain.
  - Volume 16., 1948; 8 (Reel 9)
    May 1948-September 1948. 79 pp.: The Iron Curtain; "Hollywood 10" contempt trials; anti-trust suit against studios on issue of blacklisting; Screen Writers Guild; press on anti-communism and the motion picture industry.
  - Volume 17., 1948-1949; 9 (Reel 9)
    October 1948-March 1949. 87 pp.: HUAC Hollywood hearings; anti-trust suit against studios on issue of blacklisting; Screen Writers Guild; "Hollywood 10" activities; blacklist issue; John Howard Lawson; "red-baiting" films and plays; labor disputes; "Hollywood 10" law suits against studios; Walk a Crooked Mile; Eric Johnston; anti-Semitism and racial intolerance in motion picture industry.
- News clippings - April 1949-December 1958. (Reel 10)
  - Volume 18., 1949; 1 (Reel 10)
    April 1949-June 1949. 94 pp.: Anti-Communist films; Dalton Trumbo; Screen Writers Guild; racism and Home of the Brave; "Hollywood 10" anti-trust law suit against the studios; Red Menace; "Hollywood 10" activities; Albert Maltz and book The Journey of Simon McKeever.
  - Volume 19., 1949-1950; 2 (Reel 10)
    July 1949-March 1950. 131 pp.: Anti-Communist films; Ayn Rand; racist films issue; "Hollywood Beat" column and David Platt column [motion picture and industry commentaries]; protest support for "Hollywood 10"; CSU activities; strike activities; "Hollywood 10" activities; Negro stereotype in films; Roberto Rossellini.
  - Volume 20., 1950; 3 (Reel 10)
    April 1950-June 1950. 89 pp.: John Howard Larson; Dalton Trumbo; New York City's Deadline for Freedom Rallies in support of "Hollywood 10"; "Hollywood 10" activities; US Supreme Court decision on "Hollywood 10" appeal; David Platt column [motion picture and industry commentaries]; appeal for re-hearing of "Hollywood 10"; international support of "Hollywood 10"; appeal to United Nations on behalf of "Hollywood 10"; blacklist issue.
  - Volume 21., 1950; 4 (Reel 10)
    July 1950-December 1950. 76 pp.: "Hollywood 10" activities; international support of "Hollywood 10"; Harry M. Warner on Communist infiltration; Motion Picture Alliance; public support for "Hollywood 10"; David Platt column [motion picture and industry commentaries].
  - Volume 22., 1951; 5 (Reel 10)
    January 1951-May 1951. 144 pp.: David Platt column [motion picture and industry commentaries]; HUAC hearings; V.J. Jerome; Gale A. Sondergaard; Motion Picture Alliance; Larry Parks; Actors Equity Association; I Was A Communist For The FBI; Roy M. Brewer; David Platt column [motion picture and industry commentaries].
  - Volume 23., 1951-1952; 6 (Reel 10)
    June 1951-February 1952. 94 pp.: HUAC hearings; Ronald Reagan; Martin Berkeley; Hollywood ASP activities; blacklisting issue; Sidney Buchman.
  - Volume 24., 1952-1953; 7 (Reel 10)
    March 1952-March 1953. 125 pp.: "Hollywood 10" law suit against studios; American Legion support of anti-Communist activities; Paul Jarrico; blacklisting issue; RKO Radio Pictures; Edward G. Robinson; Clifford Odets; Ronald Reagan; HUAC hearings; Charles Chaplin; The Salt of the Earth; lawsuits against studios alleging blacklisting; Libby Burke.
  - Volume 25., 1953-1955; 8 (Reel 10)
    April 1953-March 1955. 118 pp.: HUAC hearings; Screen Actors Guild; television industry; Actors Equity Association; Edward Dmytryk; David Platt column [motion picture and industry commentaries]; The Salt of the Earth; Roy M. Brewer; reviews of Soviet and other foreign films.
  - Volume 26., 1955-1958; 9 (Reel 10)
    April 1955-December 1958. 63 pp.: David Platt column [motion picture and industry commentaries]; Blackboard Jungle; The Salt of the Earth; Arthur Miller; lawsuits against studios alleging blacklisting; "Hollywood 10" activities.
- Bureau File #100-138754 (Reel 11)
  - Enclosure to Serial 4., 1938-1940; 1 (Reel 11)
    29 pp. League of American Writers; IATSE convention proceedings
  - Enclosure to Serial 163., 1947; 2 (Reel 11)
    27 pp. List of Communist party members employed in the motion picture industry, June 11, 1947.
  - Enclosure to Serial 157X., 1947; 3 (Reel 11)
    317 pp. Report entitled Communist Infiltration of Motion Picture Industry, Up to Date as of May 24, 1947.
  - Enclosure to Serial 188., 1940; 4 (Reel 11)
    34 pp. IATSE convention proceedings, 1940; The Daily Worker articles on film as propaganda.
  - Enclosure to Serial 238., 5 (Reel 11)
    11 pp. Statement on motion picture industry and congressional investigations.
  - Enclosure to Serial 250., 1947; 6 (Reel 11)
    71 pp. July 8, 1947 report entitled Communist Infiltration of the Motion Picture Industry.
  - Enclosure to Serial 251X., 1947; 7 (Reel 11)
    357 pp. Biographical sketches, highlighting Communist "connections" of witnesses appearing before HUAC in 1947.
  - Enclosure to Serial 251X1., 1947; 8 (Reel 11)
    205 pp. Report entitled Summary on the Communist Infiltration into the Motion Picture Industry, October 2, 1947.
  - Enclosure to Serial 360., 9 (Reel 11)
    16 pp. Hollywood Reporter and Variety articles regarding reaction to HUAC investigations; Hollywood ASP flyer.
- Bureau File #100-138754 (Reel 12)
  - Enclosure to Serial 391., 1947; 1 (Reel 12)
    279 pp.: HUAC hearings transcripts, October 20-24 and 28-30, 1947.
  - Enclosure to Serial 455., 2 (Reel 12)
    25 pp.: Myron C. Fagan on Thieves' Paradise.
  - Enclosure to Serial 464., 3 (Reel 12)
    5 pp.: Title page and Foreword of Gordon Kahn's book entitled Hollywood on Trial: The Story of the 10 Who Were Indicted.
  - Enclosure to Serial 469., 1948; 4 (Reel 12)
    21 pp.: Transcripts of Abe Polonsky's telephone conversations of March 20, 1948.
  - Enclosure to Serial 491., 5 (Reel 12)
    45 pp.: Myron C. Fagan.
  - Enclosure to Serial 494., 6 (Reel 12)
    33 pp.: Investigation of the New York theater industry; New Theatre League.
  - Enclosure to Serial 500., 7 (Reel 12)
    29 pp.: Cinema Educational Guild theater play entitled Mr. X.
  - Enclosure to Serial 534., 8 (Reel 12)
    30 pp.: Myron C. Fagan; Catholic Stage Guild in Ireland; Gregory Peck.
  - Enclosure to Serial 541., 9 (Reel 12)
    6 pp.: Title page from Myron C. Fagan's book entitled Red Treason in Hollywood.
  - Enclosure to Serial 554., 10 (Reel 12)
    80 pp.: Amici curiae brief in Lawson v. U.S. and Trumbo v. U.S.@ Dalton Trumbo's pamhplet on the "Hollywood 10" entitled The Time of the Toad.
- Bureau File #100-138754 (Reel 13)
  - Enclosure to Serial 637., 1 (Reel 13)
    67 pp.: Public correspondence with US Supreme Court regarding the Eugene Dennis Contempt Case and "Hollywood 10".
  - Enclosure to Serial 826., 2 (Reel 13)
    45 pp.: Script of The Troubled Air.
  - Enclosure to Serial 831., 1951; 3 (Reel 13)
    221 pp.: HUAC hearing transcripts, May 16-18, 1951; Roy M. Brewer testimony.
  - Enclosure to Serial 834., 4 (Reel 13)
    20 pp.: Press articles on the alleged Communist infiltration of Hollywood.
  - Enclosure to Serial 836., 1951; 5 (Reel 13)
    128 pp.: HUAC hearing transcripts, May 24, 1951 and April 24, 1951.
  - Enclosure to Serial 839., 1951; 6 (Reel 13)
    113 pp.: HUAC hearings transcripts, April 25, 1951; Edward Dmytryk.
  - Enclosure to Serial 1003., 1949; 7 (Reel 13)
    583 pp.: Report entitled Summary on the Communist Infiltration Into the Motion Picture Industry, July 15, 1949.
- Bureau File #100-138754 (Reel 14)
  - Enclosure to Serial 1006., 1952; 1 (Reel 14)
    51 pp.: HUAC hearings transcripts, November 12-13, 1952.
  - Enclosure to Serial 1025., 1953; 2 (Reel 14)
    422 pp.: HUAC hearings transcripts, March 26-28, 30-31, and April 7-8, 1953.
  - Enclosure to Serial 1047., 3 (Reel 14)
    99 pp.: Cinema Educational Guild pamphlet encompassing Myron C. Fagan's article entitled Red Treason on Broadway; Lucille Ball.
  - Enclosure to Serial 1103., 1955; 4 (Reel 14)
    523 pp.: Report entitled Summary on the Communist into the Motion Picture Industry (Up to Date as of December 31, 1955).
  - Supplemental Release Materials, 1948-1958; 5 (Reel 14)
    26 pp.: Synopses of Communist infiltration of the Motion Picture Industry by D.M. Ladd for J. Edgar Hoover; Michael Seymour Blankfort.
  - Other Agency Documents Approved for Release by the FBI, 1943-1947; 6 (Reel 14)
    40 pp.: OWI review of script for Secret Service in Darkest Africa; Office of Censorship cable intercepts from USSR to the American Cinematographer in Hollywood.
- Guide to the Microfilm Collection (Reel 15)